Guide to the Tjalling Charles Koopmans papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Tjalling Charles Koopmans papers
1954-1984
MS 1439
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
13.25
(32 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, subject files, and material which document Tjalling Koopmans's professional career as an economist, author, and educator. The papers include files relating to his research, professional affiliations, and writings.
Koopmans, Tjalling C. (Tjalling Charles), 1910-1985
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Tjalling C. Koopmans, 1986, and the Cowles Foundation, 1988 and 1991.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: I. Correspondence II. Research Files.
Biographical / Historical
Tjalling Charles Koopmans was born in Holland on August 28, 1910. He graduated from the University of Utrecht (M.A., 1933) and the University of Leiden (Ph.D., 1936), and was director of research for the Cowles Commission (1948-1954). At Yale University, Koopmans served as professor of economics (1955-1985), director of the Cowles Foundation (1961-1967), and Alfred Cowles Professor of Economics (1967-1985). He received the Nobel Prize in Economics in 1975. Koopmans died in 1985.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, subject files, and material which document Tjalling Koopmans's professional career as an economist, author, and educator. The papers include files relating to his research, professional affiliations, and writings.
Economics; Koopmans, Tjalling C. (Tjalling Charles), 1910-1985; Cowles Commission for Research in Economics; Yale University -- Faculty
- Correspondence, Series I
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1977, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Economic Association
    - General, 1957-1984, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Executive Committee, 1974-1978, undated (Box 1, Folder 4-7)
    - Handbook, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Meetings, 1978, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
    - President, 1977, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
    - Presidential address, 1977, 1978, undated (Box 1, Folder 13-15)
  - American Physical Society, 1978, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Annual Review of Energy, 1977-1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
  - Approaches to Business Cycle Analysis, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Arms control
    - General, 1977-1983, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Seminar, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
  - Association of American Universities, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Australia, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Awards and prizes, 1972-1981 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Berlsowitz project, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - The Bias in Single-Equation Methods..., 1944 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Book reviews, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Boston meeting, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Bruno, Michael, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Carry over problems, 1946, 1956, undated (Box 2, Folder 31-33)
  - Catholic University of Louvain, 1965-1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Causal ordering, 1959-1982, undated (Box 2, Folder 35-36)
  - Causal Ordering for General Equilibrium Analysis, 1978-1980, undated (Box 2, Folder 37-38)
  - Center for Advanced Studies in the Behavioral Sciences, 1958-1977, undated (Box 2, Folder 39-40)
  - Christ monograph, 1955-1964, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Chronological files, 1978 January - 1983 July (Box 3, Folder 42-59)
  - Citation Classics, 1976-1983 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Committee-on Nuclear and Alternative Energy Systems (CONAES)
    - Modeling Resource Group
      - General, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 61-66)
      - Brooks comments, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 67)
      - Correspondence, 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 68-69)
      - Documents, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 70)
      - Publication, 1977, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 71)
      - Report requests, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 72)
      - Reprinting, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 73-74)
      - Responses to reports, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 75)
      - Taylor memo, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 76)
      - Yale staffing, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Comparisons of systems, 1968-1970, undated (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Conferences
    - General, 1963-1980 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Activity analysis, 1963, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Business expectations, 1955-1958 (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Cross section data and time study, 1957, undated (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Institute of Philosophy, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - International Economic Association, Spain, 1973-1976, undated (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Linear programming, Princeton, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Mathematical Social Science Board, University of Pennsylvania, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Torun, Poland, 1973-1975, undated (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Cowles Foundation
    - Reports, 1959-1982 (Box 5, Folder 89-91)
    - Seminars, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Cowles, Alfred, 1955-1977 (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Cowles Professorship of Economics, 1967-1975 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - George Dantzig volume, 1977-1983, undated (Box 6, Folder 95)
  - Debreu, Gerard, 1982, undated (Box 6, Folder 96)
  - Design of Experiments, undated (Box 6, Folder 97)
  - Dispersal, 1951-1957, undated (Box 6, Folder 98)
  - Disposal of books, 1983, undated (Box 6, Folder 99)
  - Disposal of journals and offprints, 1969-1982, undated (Box 6, Folder 100-101)
  - Durable Consumers' Goods and the Prevention of Post-War Inflation, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 102)
  - Earth Day, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 103)
  - The Econometric Approach to Business Fluctuations, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 104)
  - Econometric Society
    - General, 1952-1983 (Box 6, Folder 105)
    - Aide memoire, 1959, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - Council, 1968-1976 (Box 6, Folder 107-108)
    - Editorial Committee, 1967, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - Fellows, 1973-1984 (Box 6, Folder 110-111)
    - Finances, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - Meetings
      - General, 1955-1984 (Box 7, Folder 113-114)
      - Athens, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 115)
      - Buenos Aires, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 116)
      - Helsinki, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 117)
      - Latin America, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 118)
      - Oslo, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 119)
      - Toronto, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 120)
    - World Congress
      - Aix-en-Provence, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 121)
      - Cambridge, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 322)
      - Choice of location, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 123)
      - Toronto, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 124-126)
  - Econometrica, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 127)
  - Economics 366, 1970-1981, undated (Box 7, Folder 128-129)
  - Economics 95-10a (115a), 1972, 1975 undated (Box 7, Folder 130)
  - Economics 95-10b (115b), 1969-1975, undated (Box 7, Folder 131-132)
  - Economics 97-2a (192a), 1976, undated (Box 8, Folder 133-134)
  - Economics 107a/108a, 1971-1973, undated (Box 8, Folder 135-136)
  - Economics 108b, 1968-1972 (Box 8, Folder 137)
  - Economics 117a, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 138)
  - Economics 500a, 1977, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 139-140)
  - Economics 511b, 1972-1979, undated (Box 8, Folder 141)
  - Economics 542a (460a), 1975-1981, undated (Box 8, Folder 142-144)
  - Economics 542b (460b), 1978, 1979, undated (Box 8, Folder 145-148)
  - Economic Department: Fisher Chair, 1965-1972 (Box 9, Folder 149-150)
  - Economics of shipping
    - General, 1913, 1924, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 151-152)
    - World War II, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 153)
  - Electric power generation, 1964-1969, undated (Box 9, Folder 154-155)
  - Energetic modelers, 1972-1974 (Box 9, Folder 156)
  - Energy
    - Conference, M.I.T, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 157)
    - Greenberger project, 1981 1982 (Box 9, Folder 158-159)
    - Journals, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 160)
    - Modeling Committee, 1972-1979 (Box 9, Folder 161-162)
    - Modeling Resource Group, 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 163-164)
    - Policy Project, 1972-1975 (Box 9, Folder 165)
    - Research support, undated (Box 9, Folder 166)
    - Seminar, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 167)
    - Ways of looking, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 168)
  - Energy Modeling Forum: Elasticities, 1976-1978 (Box 10, Folder 169)
  - Examinations in Statistics, 1941-1954, undated (Box 10, Folder 170-171)
  - Exchange Ratio Between Cargoes on Various Routes ..., undated (Box 10, Folder 172)
  - Extremal problems, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 173)
  - Federation of Swedish Industries, 1975, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 174)
  - Forecasting Postwar Demands: Discussion, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 175)
  - "Foundations in Econometrics", 1953, 1954, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 176)
  - General climate studies, 1969-1974 (Box 10, Folder 177)
  - Gustavus Adolphus College, 1975-1981 (Box 10, Folder 178-179)
  - Haavelmo, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 180)
  - Hicks, J. R., 1960 (Box 10, Folder 181)
  - Hierarchies, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 182)
  - Hildreth project, 1981, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 183)
  - History of Decision Sciences, 1972-1979 (Box 10, Folder 184)
  - History of Linear-Programming, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 185)
  - History of Mathematical-Economics and Econometrics, 1949-1982 (Box 11, Folder 186-188)
  - History of Quasi-Convexity, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 189-190)
  - Honorary Degree proposals, 1965-1984 (Box 11, Folder 191)
  - Hotelling dedicatory volume, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 192)
  - Human rights, 1982-1984 (Box 11, Folder 193)
  - Hungary, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 194)
  - Hydroelectricity
    - Documents, 1945-1982 (Box 11, Folder 195-198)
    - Notes and correspondence, 1956-1960 (Box 11, Folder 199-200)
  - Identification, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 201)
  - Illinois event, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 202)
  - India, 1967-1969 (Box 12, Folder 203)
  - Indivisibilities and discreet programming, 1956-1963, undated (Box 12, Folder 204-205)
  - Instituto Matematico, 1964-1977 (Box 12, Folder 206)
  - International Association for the Study of Interdisciplinary Research, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 207)
  - International Congress of Mathematicians, 1961-1962 (Box 12, Folder 208)
  - International Economic Association
    - General, 1956-1977 (Box 12, Folder 209)
    - Fifth World Congress, 1976-1978 (Box 12, Folder 210-211)
  - International Federation for Information Processing, 1978-1982 (Box 12, Folder 212-213)
  - International Federation of Institutes for Advanced Studies, 1977-1980 (Box 12, Folder 214)
  - International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis (IIASA)
    - General, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 215)
    - Conference, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 216)
    - Directorship, 1970-1981 (Box 12, Folder 217-218)
    - Funding, 1981-1983 (Box 12, Folder 219)
    - Methodology, 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 220)
    - National Academy of Science panels, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 221)
    - Summer workshop record, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 222-223)
    - Trip, 1973, 1974, undated (Box 13, Folder 224)
  - International Scientific Forum on an Acceptable World Energy Future, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 225)
  - International Scientific Forum on Energy for Developed and Developing Countries, 1978, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 226-227)
  - International Scientific Forum Planning Committee, 1977-1980 (Box 13, Folder 228-229)
  - Invariant capital stock, 1975-1981 (Box 13, Folder 230)
  - Invitations to contribute a paper, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 231)
  - Invitations to speak, 1975-1983 (Box 13, Folder 232-233)
  - Journal-of-Economic Theory, 1967-1974 (Box 13, Folder 234)
  - Journal of Mathematical Economics, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 235)
  - Kaldor lectures, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 236)
  - Kantorovich, Leonid V.
    - General, 1956-1978, undated (Box 13, Folder 237-238)
    - Cooper-Charnes discussion, 1960-1962 (Box 14, Folder 239-240)
    - Invitation to the Institute of Management Sciences meeting, 1959, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 241)
    - Mathematical Methods of Organizing and Planning Production, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 242-243)
    - Papers and bibliographic materials, 1939-1975, undated (Box 14, Folder 244-249)
    - Translations, 1958-1960 (Box 14, Folder 250-251)
  - Koopmans, Tjalling C.
    - Biographical materials, 1981-1985, undated (Box 14, Folder 252-254)
    - Degrees, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 255)
    - Lectures
      - Case Institute, 1982, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 256)
      - University of Minnesota, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 257)
    - Monograph, undated (Box 15, Folder 258-259)
    - Outside employment, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 260)
    - Papers
      - General, 1948-1967 (Box 15, Folder 261-276)
      - General, 1968-1976, undated (Box 16, Folder 277-285)
      - "Analytical Aspects of Policy Studies", 1976 (Box 16, Folder 286)
      - "Discounting Volume", 1982 (Box 16, Folder 287)
      - "Economics Among the Sciences", 1977-1979, undated (Box 16, Folder 288-289)
      - Nobel lecture: "Concepts of Optimality and Their Uses", 1975-1979, undated (Box 16, Folder 290-291)
      - "The Transition from Exhaustible to Renewable or Inexhaustible Resources", 1978, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 292)
    - Personal correspondence
      - A-S, 1956-1984 (Box 16, Folder 293-306)
      - T-Z, 1956-1984, undated (Box 17, Folder 307-310)
      - Miscellanea, 1939-1982, undated (Box 17, Folder 311-318)
    - Research plans, 1937-1960, undated (Box 17, Folder 319)
    - Sabbatical, 1963-1979, undated (Box 17, Folder 320-321)
    - Talks, 1967-1977 May (Box 17, Folder 322-328)
    - Talks, 1977 August - 1983, undated (Box 18, Folder 329-338)
    - Travel, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 339)
  - Koopmans, Tjalling C. and Gerard Debreu
    - "Additively Decomposed Quasiconvex Functions", 1972-1983, undated (Box 18, Folder 340-342)
  - Kornai, Janos, 1965-1971, n.s. (Box 18, Folder 343)
  - Learning models, undated (Box 18, Folder 344)
  - Lindau Conference, 1976-1982 (Box 18, Folder 345)
  - Location problems, 1945-1950, undated (Box 18, Folder 346)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company
    - General, 1956, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 347-348)
    - General, 1958-1976, undated (Box 19, Folder 349-350)
    - Production, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 351)
    - Translations, 1966, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 352)
  - Mayshak, Jacob
    - Honor volume, 1961-1984, undated (Box 19, Folder 353-354)
    - Interdisciplinary colloquium, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 355)
    - Tributes, 1977, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 356)
  - "Mathematical Programming", 1970-1980, undated (Box 19, Folder 357)
  - Maximizing stationary utility, 1967-1969, undated (Box 19, Folder 358-359)
  - Michigan conference, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 360)
  - Microeconomic models, 1943-1952, undated (Box 19, Folder 361-362)
  - Model construction in the Social Sciences, 1951, 1953, undated (Box 19, Folder 363)
  - Monograph 13, 1955, 1956, undated (Box 19, Folder 361-365)
  - Monograph l4, 1953-1970, undated (Box 19, Folder 366)
  - Morgenstern project, 1952, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 367)
  - Mørk, Randall: Paper, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 368)
  - Narayanan, R.: Thesis (Box 19, Folder 369-371)
  - National Academy of Sciences
    - General, 1964-1977, undated (Box 19, Folder 372)
    - Assembly of Behavioral and Social Sciences, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 373)
    - Commission on Natural Resources, 1972, 1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 374)
    - Committees, 1971, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 375)
    - Energy panel, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 376)
    - Energy study, 1972, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 377)
    - Expenses reimbursed, 1972-1979 (Box 20, Folder 378-380)
    - Foreign secretary, 1967-1977 (Box 20, Folder 381)
    - National Research Council (NRC)
      - Committee on Basic Research, 1980, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 382)
      - Committee on Federal Science Policy, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 383)
      - Committee on Nuclear and Alternative Energy Systems, 1975-1977 (Box 20, Folder 384)
      - Synfuel study, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 385)
    - Proceedings, 1971, 1972, undated (Box 20, Folder 386-387)
    - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 388)
  - National Academy of Sciences/International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis
    - Advisory committee, 1976-1980, undated (Box 20, Folder 389-391)
    - Agendas, minutes, lists, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 392-393)
    - Global modeling, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 391)
    - Invitations, 1977, undated (Box 20, Folder 395)
    - National Academy of Sciences Evaluation, 1975-1978, n. d. (Box 20, Folder 396-397)
    - Subcommittee on System and Decision Sciences, 1977-1979, undated (Box 21, Folder 398-400)
  - National Science Foundation
    - General, 1958-1961, undated (Box 21, Folder 401-402)
    - Budget alarms, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 403)
    - Grants, 1965-1981, undated (Box 21, Folder 404-409)
    - Proposal, 1975, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 410)
    - Reviews of proposals, 1972, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 411)
  - Netherlands School of Economics, 1963, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 412)
  - New York Times, 1978, 1982, undated (Box 21, Folder 413)
  - New Zealand, 1967-1969, undated (Box 21, Folder 414)
  - Nobel economists: interview project, 1979-1981, undated (Box 21, Folder 415)
  - Nobel Prize, 1969-1981, undated (Box 21, Folder 416-417)
  - Nobel Prize volume and lecture, 1975, 1976, undated (Box 21, Folder 418)
  - Operations Research Society of America/The Institute of Management Sciences: Meeting, 1976, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 419-420)
  - Periodicals, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 421)
  - Poland, 1964, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 422)
  - Power generation, 1969-1971, undated (Box 22, Folder 423)
  - Process analysis, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 424)
  - Public statements, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 425)
  - Publishers, 1958-1977 (Box 22, Folder 426)
  - Quasi-convexity, quasi-concavity, 1961-1984 (Box 22, Folder 427-428)
  - Railroad problems, 1953, undated (Box 22, Folder 429)
  - Readings and references, 1976-1979, undated (Box 22, Folder 430)
  - Reprintings and citations, 1968-1983, undated (Box 22, Folder 431-433)
  - Research reports, 1956-1958 (Box 22, Folder 434)
  - Resources For the Future
    - Discount rate conference, 1980, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 435)
    - Ford energy study, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 436)
    - Forum: "U.S. National Interests and Global Natural Resources", 1982 (Box 22, Folder 437)
    - National Science Foundation Advisory Committee, 1978-1980 (Box 22, Folder 438)
    - Twenty-fifth anniversary, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 439)
  - River valley control, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 440)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1950-1959 (Box 22, Folder 441)
  - Samuelson, Paul A., 1955, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 442)
  - Science magazine, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 443)
  - Social Science Building, 1969, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 444)
  - "Some Early origins of Operations Research/Management Sciences", 1977 (Box 22, Folder 445)
  - Soviet exchanges, 1970-1983 (Box 22, Folder 446)
  - Soviet Union
    - General, 1963-1970, undated (Box 22, Folder 447-449)
    - Information sheets, 1963-1971, undated (Box 22, Folder 450-451)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 452)
    - Notes and papers, 1965-1970, undated (Box 23, Folder 453-456)
    - Reports on visits by others, 1969, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 457)
  - Springer reprinting project, 1968-1984, undated (Box 23, Folder 458-461)
  - Symposium: Novosibirsk, 1969, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 462)
  - Talks on Modeling Resource Group procedures, 1978, undated (Box 23, Folder 463)
  - Teaching mathematics for social scientists, 1948, 1972, undated (Box 23, Folder 464)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority, undated (Box 23, Folder 465)
  - Theory of Growth, undated (Box 23, Folder 466)
  - Thesis seminar, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 467)
  - Three Essays on the State of Economic Science
    - General, 1957-1959, undated (Box 23, Folder 468)
    - Essay I, 1954-1965, undated (Box 23, Folder 469)
    - Essay II, 1954-1956, undated (Box 23, Folder 470)
    - Essay III, 1956, 1957, undated (Box 23, Folder 471)
    - Quotations, 1956, 1957, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 472)
    - Translations, 1967-1976, undated (Box 23, Folder 473)
  - Tinbergen, Jan
    - General, 1940-1983, undated (Box 24, Folder 474-476)
    - Recollections, 1978,1983, undated (Box 24, Folder 477)
    - Volume, 1970-1973, undated (Box 24, Folder 478)
  - Translations
    - General, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 479)
    - Russian papers in Mathematical Economics, 1966-1976, undated (Box 24, Folder 480)
  - Transportation monograph, 1954-1958, undated (Box 24, Folder 481)
  - University of California
    - General, 1966-1978, undated (Box 24, Folder 482)
    - Irvine, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 483)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 484)
  - Uzawa paper, 1964-1982, undated (Box 24, Folder 485-486)
  - Vienna conference, 1969-1971 (Box 24, Folder 487)
  - von Neumann Model, 1955-1958, undated (Box 24, Folder 488)
  - Warsaw symposium, 1971-1972, undated (Box 24, Folder 489-490)
  - Weitzman, Martin, 1970, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 491)
  - Welfare economics, 1955 (Box 24, Folder 492)
  - Wiley, John and Sons, 1968-1978 (Box 24, Folder 493)
  - Winter plans, 1978-1984, undated (Box 24, Folder 494-496)
  - Wisconsin symposium, 1971, undated (Box 24, Folder 497)
  - Wold, Herman, 1946-1953, undated (Box 24, Folder 498)
  - World modeling
    - Mesarovic, Mihajlo, 1972 September-October (Box 24, Folder 499)
    - Mesarovic, Mihajlo, 1972 November - 1973 (Box 25, Folder 500-502)
  - Yale Daily News (Box 25, Folder 503)
  - Yale Institution for Social and Policy Studies, 1975-1980 (Box 25, Folder 504)
  - Yale University Press, 1956, 1972, 1978, undated (Box 25, Folder 505)
  - Miscellanea, 1931-1982, undated (Box 25, Folder 506-512)
- Research Files, Series II
  - Additive utility theory (Box 26, Folder 513)
  - Consumers and producers surplus (Box 26, Folder 514)
  - Cost-benefit analysis (Box 26, Folder 515)
  - Course notes
    - General (Box 26, Folder 516-517)
    - Mathematics (Box 26, Folder 518)
  - Energy
    - General (Box 26, Folder 519)
    - Course notes (Box 27, Folder 520-521)
    - Discounting (Box 27, Folder 522)
    - Helium (Box 27, Folder 523)
    - Reports (Box 28, Folder 526-529)
    - Resources (Box 28, Folder 530)
  - Lecture notes
    - Economic growth theory (Box 28, Folder 531-532)
    - Others: recorded by Koopmans (Box 28, Folder 533)
  - Optimal Growth Theory
    - General (Box 29, Folder 534-540)
    - General (Box 30, Folder 541-546)
    - Energy (Box 31, Folder 547)
    - Turnpike theory (Box 31, Folder 548)
  - Stationary utility. (Box 31, Folder 549-553)
  - Statistics (Box 31, Folder 554)
- Additional Material, 1954-1984; Accession 1989-M-009; 1 box (.25 linear feet)
  Scope and Contents
  Addition Inventory by Carol King 1988 Oct
  Received from: Alvin Klevorick, Cowles Foundation, 1988 Jul 1
  - Cowles Foundation
    - Anderson Fellowships, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Article from the Boston Globe entitled "Bankrolled by Cowles, How economics went high-tech.", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Cowles Foundation papers distribution list, 1966-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Cowles Foundation office procedures, 1954-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ford visitors, 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Guests, 1954-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Library Committee, 1972-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Monographs, 1972-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Research assistance, 1972-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)